vikingcruises.com 2018-08-28

# Privacy Policy | Viking Cruises

**Our Privacy Policy has changed, effective on May 24th, 2018.  
To understand your opt out choices, please see the section headed "6. YOUR CHOICES, INCLUDING OPT-OUT OPTIONS" below.**

1\. INTRODUCTION 

2\. PERSONAL INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE

3\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

4\. USE OF INFORMATION 

5\. SHARING INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES

6\. YOUR CHOICES, INCLUDING OPT-OUT OPTIONS

7\. HOW WE STORE AND PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION 

8\. CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

| 

9\. NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

10\. TRANSPORTATION SECURITY ADMINISTRATION SECURE FLIGHT NOTICE

11\. LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES AND SERVICES.

12\. PRIVACY AND CHANGE OF CONTROL

13\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

14\. APPLICABLE LAW

15.YOUR COMMENTS AND QUESTIONS   
  
---|---  
  
### 1\. INTRODUCTION

This Privacy Policy of Viking River Cruises Inc. (“Viking” “we,” “our,” or “us”) explains the collection, use, and sharing of information from or about you in connection with your use of the Services. The term "Services" refers to our ocean and river cruises, including the selection of products, content, events, activities, excursions and services offered onboard and off-shore either directly by us, or through our affiliates or third-party business associates, as well as any other products, features, tools, materials, or other services offered from time to time through a variety of Access Points. The term "Access Points" refers to, collectively, our various websites ("our websites"), mobile applications, onboard media, blogs, social media and other places, and other online or wireless offerings, whether accessed via computer, mobile device or other technology, any of which is owned or operated by us or on behalf.

By viewing or otherwise using any of the Services, whether while travelling or booking travel with us, or through a registered account with us, or as a visitor to our websites or other Access Point, you consent to the collection and use of information from or about you as explained in this Privacy Policy and to our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.vikingcruises.com/terms-conditions/index.html). If you do not consent to the collection and use of information from or about you in accordance with this Privacy Policy, then you may not use the Services.

Please note that the website addresses (i.e., URLs) or other hyperlinks included within this Privacy Policy may not function as hyperlinks on all the Access Points. To view this Privacy Policy with clickable hyperlinks, please visit our websites on your computer.

Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given them in our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.vikingcruises.com/terms-conditions/index.html).

### 2\. PERSONAL INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE

Although you do not have to provide us with any personal information to visit our websites, you may not be able to fully access or use all of features and offerings of our websites and other Access Points and the Services if you choose to not provide certain “personal information.”

Personal information may include such information as your name, mailing address, billing address including ZIP code, home, business and/or mobile telephone number, email address, passport information, credit or debit card information and your Viking account user name and password and other information, including without limitation, the name, address, and telephone number of someone who is not traveling with you who we can contact in case of an emergency. We also may ask you to provide your date of birth, gender, vacation and dietary preference, health requirements and information about your interests, so that we can combine such information with the information described above. It is your responsibility to obtain the consent of other individuals in your travel party prior to providing us with their personal information, as any access to view or change their information will be available only through your account.

The personal information you provide to us will occur when

  * you interact with us or our affiliates or third-party business associates,
  * when you view or use the Services, such as when you book travel or travel with us, participate in onboard activities or take offshore excursions while traveling with us,
  * when you create a profile to register for and/or use a Viking account,
  * when you contact our customer service or other means to request information from us,
  * when we respond to your inquiries,
  * participate in sweepstakes or other promotions, access interactive services or view webcasts, review newsletters that we or our affiliates or third-party business associates may offer from time to time, or
  * you provide quotes, photos or other personal information that you provide to us when we communicate with you about the Services.

We also receive personal information when you apply for a job in the “careers” section of our websites. Any such personal information gathered through that section will be used solely to evaluate whether your background and experience make you a candidate for a career with Viking.

We may combine the information we collect from or about you, including through the tracking technologies described in Section 3 (Information We Collect), with your personal information, and use it in the manner described in this Privacy Policy or as otherwise permitted by law.

### 3\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We may collect information (including personal information) about you from other sources, such as data aggregators, public databases, and third party business partners or using technology, such as cookies. Examples of this may include information (whether identified, de-identified or anonymous, and whether collected online or offline) about your interests, demographic data, purchasing behavior, and your activities online (such as websites visited and advertisements viewed) and includes the following:

 **(a) From Third Parties Services**. We may collect information about you (including personal information) from various third party services, including from Access Points owned or operated by third parties. For example, we may receive information about you (including personal information) when you interact or connect with us or our Services, for example, by liking us on Facebook® or following us on Twitter® or on Instagram® or watching us on YouTube®. The collected information may be information associated with that third-party service, or that you elect to make public using that service or have authorized the third-party service to share with us (such as your user ID, billing information, public profile information, email address, birthday, friends list, pages you have "liked" or commented on, and other account and profile data). The information we receive is dependent upon your privacy settings with the third party. You should always review, and if necessary, adjust your privacy settings with third-parties before interacting or connecting with us through them. We are not responsible for their privacy practices or content. All product and company names are trademarks™ or registered® trademarks of their respective holders, and use of them does not imply any affiliation with or endorsement by them.

 **(b) Usage and Log Data**. In addition to the personal information that you provide or we collect as described in this Privacy Policy, we also collect non-personally identifiable information when you view the websites, use the Services or view Viking advertising or content through any of the Access Points. “Non-personally identifiable information” is information that cannot be used to identify a specific individual, and examples may include your IP address, device, browser and software characteristics (such as type and operating system), location (which may include precise location data), activity on the Services, including information, activities and content viewed, used or accessed, page views, ad data, referral URLs, network state, device identifiers or other unique identifiers and identifiers associated with browser cookies (see our description of "Data Collected Through Cookies, Pixel Tags and Similar Technologies" below in this Section 3), and carrier information.

 **(c) Data Collected Through Cookies, Pixel Tags and Similar Technologies**. Like many companies, we use various technologies to collect usage data and store preferences. These technologies may be used by us directly or through third party service providers. These technologies are discussed below.

  *  **Cookies and Local Storage**. One technology we use is called a cookie, which is a small data file that is transferred to your computer’s hard disk. We may collect information through other kinds of local storage (also referred to as "Flash cookies" or sometimes called “browser cookies”, because these technologies are similar to browser cookies, even though they may be stored in different parts of your computer. Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. You can instruct your browser, by changing its settings, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. While it is possible to disable cookies or delete information contained in cookies, this may interfere with the performance and features of the Services, such as preventing us from storing your preferences or login information.
  *  **Pixel tags and web beacons**. We use other technologies such as web beacons or pixel tags or clear GIFs, which can be embedded in web pages, videos, or emails, to collect certain types of information from your browser or device, such as tracking whether (and when) the recipient opened the email message. These technologies are used in conjunction with cookies and send information such as your IP address, when you viewed the page or email, the type of device or browser you use, and your location.
  *  **Mobile Device Identifiers and Software Development Kits ("SDKs" )**. When you access the Access Points by or through a mobile device, we may receive or collect and store a unique identification number associated with your device (“Device ID”), mobile carrier, device type and manufacturer, and phone number. We may use or work with third parties including our third party business partners and service providers who use mobile SDKs to collect information, such as advertising identifiers (e.g., "ad-ID" or "IDFA") and information related to how mobile devices interact with the Services. An SDK is computer code that app developers can include in their apps to enable ads to be shown, data to be collected and related services and functionality to be implemented. A mobile SDK is in effect the mobile application version of a pixel tag or beacon. We may use this technology, for instance, to analyze how you interact with our content and devices.
  *  **Analytics Tools**. We, our affiliates and/or our third party business associates may also collect analytics data, or use third-party analytics tools, to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Access Points and for other purposes.
  *  **Location Specific Information**. If you use a mobile device, a social media account or location-enabled products and services, you may be sending us information such as GPS data which reveals your actual location.

The use of these various technologies discussed in this Section 3(c) (Data Collected Through Cookies, Pixel Tags and Similar Technologies) in connection with the Services is explained further below in Section 4 (Use of Information). To learn about opting out of interest-based or online behavioral advertising, please see the information we have provided in Section 6 below (“Your Choices About Your Information”).

### 4\. USE OF INFORMATION

 **(a) Use in General.** We use the information (including personal information) we collect from or about you (including without limitation, through technologies such as those described in Section 3 (Data Collected Through Cookies, Pixel Tags and Similar Technologies) primarily to provide better customer service to you, to improve and customize the content you see, to help recognize you when you use other devices, to provide the Services you request, and to contact you about special promotions and new Services and for purposes including the following:

  * customizing or personalizing the Services and evaluating how well the Services perform;
  * customizing, targeting or personalizing our advertising that you view and monitoring the effectiveness of our email communications and other advertising efforts;
  * to provide you with the Services you request; to provide you with your travel reservation booking confirmation and updates; to manage your account, including processing bills and providing travel notifications;
  * remembering information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visits to, or the next time you visit, the Access Points;
  * to reward you as part of any reward and recognition program you choose to join;
  * to solicit information from you, including through surveys;
  * to resolve disputes, collect fees, or troubleshoot problems
  * monitoring the effectiveness of the Access Points;
  * identifying what information about our Services you may share;
  * contacting you for a sweepstakes or other promotion about a product or service we believe may be of interest to you, travel-related or otherwise, either from us alone or together with another sponsor or a third party;
  * conducting research;
  * compiling aggregate data for internal and external business purposes;
  * monitoring the aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, usage, and demographic patterns on the Access Points;
  * diagnosing or fixing technology problems;
  * preventing potentially illegal or harmful activities, including fraud;
  * protecting your and our rights;
  * other uses in accordance with our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.vikingcruises.com/terms-conditions/index.html);
  * planning for, improving and enhancing our Services; and
  * any other purpose that is required or permitted by law or that is disclosed to you at the time we collect the information or that is related to a request made by you.

 **(b) Use of Payment Information.** We use payment information, such as credit card numbers and billing ZIP code, to complete your reservations and provide the Services to you. For example, we use payment information to process payments for Services (we use a third-party payment processor to do this), to retrieve account information, to determine whether you are eligible for promotions, and to detect abuse of the Services.

 **(c) Use of Aggregate or De-Identified Information.** In addition to the information (including personal information) described in this Privacy Policy, we may aggregate information about you and other individuals together, or otherwise "de-identify" the information about you (which means that the information does not identify you personally). We may use information in these forms for any legitimate business purpose, including without limitation, for research and analysis, administration of the Services, advertising (e.g., improving our targeting efforts or our Services), and promotional purposes.

 **(d) Use of Location Data.** In order to access certain of the Services from your mobile device or browser, you may be required to share your device’s precise location data (e.g., latitude and longitude) with us. This location data may be used to provide tailored Services to you based on your location. To learn more about your choices with respect to our collection and use of location data, please see the information we have provided in Section 6 below “Your Choices About Your Information”).

 **(e) Use of Cookies, Pixel Tags And Other Tracking Technology.** A cookie lets us help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the Access Points and may also convey information to us about how you use the Access Points or our Services (e.g., the pages you view, the links you click, how frequently you access the Access Points, and other actions you take on the Access Points, and allow us to track your purchase or usage of our Services over time. We may use cookies to collect log file information (anonymous information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, information about your mobile device, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks and how you interact with links on our website, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information) about your browser or mobile device each time you access our websites. The information allows for more accurate reporting and improvement of our websites and other Access Points.

We may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to monitor aggregate usage by our visitors and customers and web traffic routing on the Services, and to customize our content and Services. These uses allow us to improve our Services. We may create a unique device or user ID for you and store it in a cookie so we can customize your experience based on your preferences.

Viking and our third-party advertising companies use pixel tags in HTML-enabled email and on our Access Points to track whether (and when) the recipient opened the message. check whether you have viewed a particular web page, ad, or email message, and determine, among other things, the time and date on which you viewed or accessed the Services, the IP address of your computer, and the URL of the web page from which the Services were viewed or accessed. To learn more about your choices with respect to our collection and use of cookies, please see the information we have provided in Section 6 below “Your Choices About Your Information”).

 **(f) Analytics Tools.** The analytics tools that collect information sent by your browser or mobile device, including the pages you visit, your use of third party applications, and other information assists us in analyzing and improving the Access Points.

### 5\. SHARING INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES

We may share your information (including personal information) only in the instances described below. We may also share your information in other circumstances with your consent. 

  * **Parent Company and Affiliates**. We may share your information (including personal information) with our parent company and corporate affiliates. This sharing enables us to fulfill the Services, as travel may be provided on a vessel owned or operated by an corporate affiliate, as well as to provide you with information about other products and services, which we believe might interest you. To the extent that our parent company and corporate affiliates have access to your information, they will follow practices that are at least as restrictive as the practices described in this Privacy Policy.
  *  **Travel and Activity Providers**. We may share information (including personal information) with airline, lodging, offshore excursion and other activity providers, who work with us to provide the Services to you or when you have made reservations with them through us as part of the Services. By requesting the excursion or activity or making a reservation as part of the Services, you are authorizing us to disclose to the provider the information (including personal information) required to complete the reservation and provide the travel, lodging, excursion or activity. Please note that these providers also may contact you as necessary to obtain additional information about you, facilitate your reservation with them, or respond to a review you may submit. While we may share anonymous reviews with our suppliers, we will not share reviewer names or contact information unless you have explicitly permitted us to do so. Please note that providers are not controlled by us and personal information disclosed to them is subject to the applicable provider's privacy policy and security practices. Therefore, we encourage you to review the privacy policies of any provider.
  *  **Third-party vendors**. We may share information (including personal information) with third-party vendors who provide functions on our behalf, including credit card processing, business analytics, customer service, marketing, distribution of surveys or sweepstakes programs, and fraud prevention. We may also authorize third-party vendors to collect information on our behalf, including as necessary to operate features of our websites and other Access Points. Third-party vendors have access to and may collect personal information) only as needed to perform their functions and are not permitted to share or use the information for any other purpose and are required to adopt data security practices consistent with our practices.
  * We may from time to time contract with third party vendors to serve ads to our customers on our behalf across the Internet or to send our direct mail to customers whom we think may be interested in our products or services. To do this, the vendors will collect anonymous information about your visits to our Web site and your interaction with our products and services. This anonymous information is collected through the use of a cookie or pixel tag – industry standard technology used by most major Web sites. No personally identifiable information is collected in this process. They may also pool the anonymous information that they collect with other sources of information not collected during your visit to our website, which may include your name and mailing address, for purposes of determining whether you might be interested in receiving a catalog.
  *  **Business partners**. We may share information (including personal information) with our third party business partners with whom we (i) may jointly offer products or services or sweepstakes or other promotions, travel-related and otherwise, or (ii) whose products or services may be offered through or on the Access Points or on our cruises; or (iii) who we believe may have travel-related or other products and services that may be of interest to you. You can tell when a third party is involved in a product or service you have requested because their name will appear, either alone or with ours. Please note that third-party business partners are not controlled by us and personal information disclosed to them is subject to the applicable third party’s privacy policy and security practices. Therefore, we encourage you to review the privacy policies of third-party business partner.
  * Referring websites. If you were referred to the Access Points from a third party website (for example, through a link you clicked on another site that directed you to the Access Point), we may share some information about you with that referring website. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any website that referred you to our Access Points.
  *  **Social media providers**. When you access certain social media features through the Access Points, you are sharing information with the social media provider (such as Facebook) and the information you share will be governed by their privacy policies (including that we may access such information via the social media provider). You may be able to modify your privacy settings for these social media providers. Please consult the privacy policy of the relevant social media provider for further information. We will not provide any other social media provider with access to your Viking account number or information. You may choose to disable such sharing of information by editing your privacy settings on that social media provider.

We also may share your information (including your personal information):

  * In response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; with law enforcement agencies as required; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law, including as described in Section 10 (Transportation Security Administration Secure Flight Notice). In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us;
  * to enforce our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.vikingcruises.com/terms-conditions/index.html), or any other agreement we or another party may have with you, and/or
  * when we believe it is appropriate to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities or exercise, defend or protect the rights, property or safety of our company, our customers, our websites or other Access Points or others.

We may also aggregate or otherwise strip data of all personally identifying characteristics and may share that aggregated, anonymized data with third parties for market and research purposes or for other purposes. For further information on your choices regarding your personal information, see Section 6 below “Your Choices About Your Information”).

### 6\. YOUR CHOICES ABOUT YOUR INFORMATION

You have the following choices regarding how we and third parties use certain information collected from or about you:

  *  **How to Control Your Communication Preferences**  
You can stop receiving promotional email communications from us by clicking on the “unsubscribe link” provided in such communications. We make every effort to promptly process all unsubscribe requests. You may not opt out of Services-related communications (e.g., account verification, information about your orders, bookings, cruises, changes/updates to our websites, products or features of our Services, technical and security notices). Please allow up to 2 weeks to be unsubscribed from all of our emails.
  *  **Opting Out of Cookies or Pixels**  
You may “opt out” of the collection of any information through cookies, pixels or other tracking technology by managing them on your browser or mobile device. However, if you decide not to accept such tracking technology from us or from our third party vendor’s or partner’s cookies, your ability to use some features on our websites and other Access Points may be impaired. Please refer to your browser’s or mobile device’s technical information for instructions on how to delete and disable cookies, pixels and other tracking/recording tools. (To learn more about cookies, pixels, clear gifs/web beacons and related technologies and how you may opt-out of some of this tracking, you may wish to visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s online resources at [http://www.networkadvertising.org)](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). Depending on your mobile device, you may not be able to control tracking technologies through settings. If you have any questions about opting out of the collection of cookies and other tracking/recording tools, you can contact us as provided in Section 15 (Your Comments and Questions).
  *  **Modifying, correcting, or Deleting Your Information**  
If you have any questions about reviewing, modifying, requesting the correction of, or deleting your information, you can contact us directly at the contact information in Section 15 below (Your Comments and Questions). Viking Cruises may retain your information for a commercially reasonable time for backup, legal, archival, or audit purposes. You can submit your request at [Data Subject Request Form](http://www.vikingcruises.com/notice).

### 7\. HOW WE STORE AND PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION

 **(a) Storage and Processing** Your information collected through the Access Points and while providing the Services may be stored and processed in the United States or in the cloud or any other country in which Viking or its subsidiaries, affiliates or service providers or their subcontractors maintain facilities. If you are located in Canada, the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that we may transfer information, including personal information, to a country and jurisdiction that does not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction, and you consent to the transfer of information to the U.S. or any other country in which Viking or its parent, subsidiaries, affiliates or service providers maintain facilities and the use and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Policy. As a result, this information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in those jurisdictions according to laws in those jurisdictions.

 **(b) Keeping Your Information Safe.** Viking cares about the security of your information, and uses commercially reasonable physical, administrative, and technological safeguards to help preserve the integrity and security of all information collected through our website. However, no security system is impenetrable and we cannot guarantee the security of our systems 100%. In the event that any information under our control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, Viking will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation and where appropriate, notify those individuals whose information may have been compromised and take other steps, in accordance with any applicable laws and regulations.

### 8\. CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

Viking does not knowingly collect or solicit any information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register on any Access Points. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without appropriate permission from their parent/legal guardian, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from a child under 13, please contact us as provided in Section 15 (Your Comments and Questions).

### 9\. NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, California residents have the right to request in writing from businesses with whom they have an established business relationship, (a) a list of the categories of personal information, such as name, e-mail and mailing address including billing ZIP code and the type of services provided to the customer, that a business has disclosed to third parties (including affiliates that are separate legal entities) during the immediately preceding calendar year for the third parties' direct marketing purposes and (b) the names and addresses of all such third parties. To request the above information, please contact us as provided in Section 15 (Your Comments and Questions). We will respond to such requests for information access within 30 days following receipt at the e-mail or mailing address stated above. Please note that we are only required to respond to each customer once per calendar year.

Additionally, California law requires that we indicate whether we honor “Do Not Track” settings in your browser concerning targeted advertising. We do not currently alter our practices when a Do Not Track signal is received. To learn about Do Not Track and for information about how to opt out of receiving targeted advertising, please click [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/).

### 10\. TRANSPORTATION SECURITY ADMINISTRATION SECURE FLIGHT NOTICE

Under the authority of 49 U.S.C. section 114, the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 and 49 C.F.R. parts 1540 and 1560 for all commercial air travel within, into or out of the United States which is booked on or after August 15, 2009, the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) requires you to provide your full name, date of birth, and gender for the purpose of watch list screening.

You may also provide your Redress Number, if available. As required by law, we will request information from you about your commercial air travel within, into or out of the United States in conjunction with your voyage and forward it to the TSA. Failure to provide your full name, date of birth, and gender may result in denial of transport or denial of authority to enter the boarding area.

Information we or you provide to the TSA may be shared by the agency with law enforcement, intelligence agencies, or others under its published system of records notice. Please see the TSA website at [www.tsa.gov](https://www.tsa.gov/) for more information on the TSA’s privacy policies.

### 11\. LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES AND SERVICES

The Access Points may integrate with or contain links to other third party websites and services. We are not responsible for the practices employed by third party websites or services embedded in, linked to, or linked from the Access Points and your interactions with any third-party website or service are subject to that third party’s own rules and policies.

### 12\. PRIVACY AND CHANGE OF CONTROL

In the event Viking or its parent company goes through a business transition, such as a merger, reorganization, financing, change of control, or acquisition or sale of all or a portion of our business, we may transfer your information, including personal information, as part of the transaction.

### 13\. CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

By using the Services or accessing the Access Points, you consent to the collection, use and storage of your information by us or our third party business associates in the manner described in this Privacy Policy and elsewhere on the Access Points. We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. If this Privacy Policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties. Your continued access to the Access Points and/or use of any of our websites or purchase or use of the Services after any such changes constitutes your acceptance of, and agreement to be legally bound by, this Privacy Policy, as revised.

### 14\. APPLICABLE LAW

Viking Rivers Services Inc. is headquartered in the U.S. and the Services are intended for individuals in the U.S and Canada. By using the Services or accessing the Access Points, you consent to the collection, storage, and processing of information under U.S. laws and as provide by this Privacy Policy.

### 15\. YOUR COMMENTS AND QUESTIONS

If you have any questions or comments regarding our privacy policy or our websites or the Access Points, you can send us an email at [customerrelations@vikingcruises.com](mailto:customerrelations@vikingcruises.com) or contact our Customer Relations department at (877)523-0579 or contact us by mail addressed to:

Attention: Customer Relations   
Viking Cruises   
5700 Canoga Avenue, Suite 200   
Woodland Hills, CA 91367

Version May 2018
